The most important thing to know when beginning your journey as a submissive is to
understand consent and your boundaries. So any actions or even anything you
talk about on cam should be consensual, which means that it's within your boundaries
that you feel safe and happy to be at talking about or exploring any of these areas
on cam. The difference between fantasy and reality on webcam versus
in-person submission is that you can switch off your laptop, close the screen, kick
somebody out whenever you want ,so you're in total control.
A good way to establish and maintain your boundaries as a submissive is to establish
a safe word with your dominant. You might also establish an amber
word which means when something's going a little bit too far but you just want to
rein it back in and not completely stop what you're doing. You might establish a word
such as amber and that you can communicate with your Dom that you might want to step
it back a little bit. A common misconception about the submissive dominant
relationship is that the dominant takes all the control and holds all the power.
In actual fact the submissive in the relationship is the one who can stop or start
an action at any time purely by giving their safe word or their amber word which
means, actually, as the submissive you hold the power and the control over what's going
on and what play is taking place. It might be a good idea to establish your boundaries
as a starting out submissive before you go on webcam so that you're not making decisions
in the split-second. Sit down with a piece of paper and write out what you're not
prepared to do, what you might do and what you're okay with doing so that you know
you've got a good starting point. Throughout your journey as a submissive remember
that your boundaries might change so they might change from month to month as you
become comfortable with more things or less things, or they might change from person
to person, you might feel better doing some things with one person and not prepared
to do it with another and that's totally fine.
Remember to look after your mental health - if you feel in any way triggered just stop
what you're doing, that's okay you don't need an excuse.
Follow your energy, do what feels good, if something's exciting or it feels good, do
more of that, and if you're triggered by something, don't feel that you have to do
it.